in linkedin.com/in/jandujo

presume.vytes.net

Jonathan Andujo Flores

Senior Software Engineer

+52 614 217 1150
Cancún, México

jandujo@vytes.net

CAREER SUMMARY

I have 12 years of experience in Information Technology Companies, working in multicultural environments, and collaborating in global teams. Performing as a software Architect focused on Microsoft's technologies and modern JavaScript frameworks. Building platforms through CD/CI for different environments and business models. Building leadership and open communication atmosphere to encourage as a successful project. Pursuing continuous improvement adding value to the customers in order to get profitable relationships with the client.

SKILLS & TOOLS

WORK EXPERIENCE

Backend

.Net 5 .Net Core (2.0, 2.1, 2.2, 3.1)
.Net Framework C#

SQL Server Entity Framework

Frontend

Angular (7, 10) Angular.js

Vuc.js HTML/CSS/SASS

TypeScript JavaScript

Silverlight React

DevOps

Azure Blob Storage

Function app Storage Queue

SQL Pipeline App Service

Logic Apps AWS S3 EC2

IAM RDS Elastic Beanstalk

Route 53 CodeBuild Cognito

CodePipeline CodeCommit

Others



DevOps

Senior Software Engineer

Software Engineer Lead

Microsoft
August 2021 - Present

Civix

November 2020 - August 2021

Automatized solutions implementing pipelines to ensure continuous integration. Mentoring about best practices implementing SOLID principles and clean code architecture

- 99.9% uptime due to pipeline using yml
- Optimizing execution time for stored procedures in 90%
- · Optimizing execution plans on MSSQL queries

Software Engineer Lead / Architect

Tiempo Development

January 2019 - October 2020

Designing solutions and leading a high-performance team to create from scratch solutions hosted in Azure to provide valued Information about 3k users using a dotnet core 3.1 framework and a JavaScript framework for frontend. Providing technical guidance and support to the team to ensure the best practices validated by SonarQube.

- Solution designing for software development and infrastructure from scratch
- Optimizing resources obtaining a decrease in cost-saving 150%
- · Decreasing bugs by applying a stronger unit test strategy

Software Engineer Lead / Architect

Grupo Ultra

April 2018 - January 2019

Conceiving multiple solutions for different departments. On the sales department was increased the revenue by applying proper business rules like fees and preferred customers. On warehouse developed a printing solution to avoid rework in labels. Implementing a helpdesk tool to keep the tracking of incidents

- Reducing the time invested in calculating fees by 25% by applying a proper architecture
- By creating different POC I define the best fit solution for the company based on the benefit-cost
- Modernizing of the core system to a cloud-based solution using AWS services

Senior Software Lead

Best Day Travel Group

October 2016 - April 2018

Backend developer at WCF that uses independent platforms to create and refactor APIs for different sources, like Google and Trivago, to show the latest deals. Making business rules to get the best prices through multiple vendor interfaces. Support for data science requirements to digest data more efficiently.

- Reengineering the solution using Redis to retrieve data results to increase performance for all the nortal
- Using multi-thread to get data from more than 1k sources per query
- Developing architecture to afford more than 150k request per second

EDUCATION

MSc IT Management

Tecmilenio University 2015 - 2017





BSc IT Engineer

Universidad Tecnológica de Chihuahua

2010 - 2015



CERTIFICATIONS AND COURSES

Microsoft

Microsoft Certified: Azure Fundamentals (AZ-900) June 2020

AWS

Cloud Practitioner Essentials (Second Edition)

May 2020

Google Activate

Web Development 2 August 2018 Web Development 1 January 2017

ATTRIBUTES

Problem Solving Goal Orientated Resourceful Assertive Communication Bilingual Avid Learner Systems Thinking

LANGUAGE

English (Proficient)

Spanish (Native)

Senior Software Lead

TAC Global Solutions

June 2014 - September 2016

Full-Stack developer for an ERP in-house system on vb.net and vb forms with a database on SQL Server. Development of a CRM system from scratch using WCF and Angular.js. Participating in a building of a mobile application for manage inbound and outbound pallets from the warehouse and forecasting cost to the customer.

- Creating KPIs to provide measures for a sales funnel inside the CRM
- · Creating a geolocation map system to track sales by state
- Ensuring the trust of the customers on their bills by implementing the forecast of the warehouse
- · Avoiding over inventory and shortage of materials in the warehouse through a solution that optimizes the consumption of materials

Full-Stack Developer

ADS Systems

July 2012 - April 2014

Designing a telemetry system using Silverlight and WCF services for getting the status of the vending machine also retrieves the sales in real-time, through RFID cards to pay. Participating in refactor for inventory system on HandHeld.

- Reducing the processing time from 2.5 hours to 15 minutes daily in reorder using CTE instead a
- Developing a telemetry system to make easier the payments for the customers
- · Collaborating on the new architecture for the ERP system

Web Developer

E Advantage

July 2011 - July 2012

Maintain well designed, efficient code by using best software development practices in HTML and CSS.

- Implementing a shop cart for step motors in a website
- · Improving a website to get better search rank in search engines such as Google and Bing using keywords

Software Engineer - Freelance

VYTES.NET

September 2007 - October 2019

Know the needs of the clients for the implementation of the best solution at low cost, architecting maintainable software that is easy for the end-user to understand.

- Resolving more than 60k requests in 25 minutes using only a server in the free tier in development for payroll system
- Developing electronic invoicing software for commercial use at low cost

Last update 08/08/2021